get a system for keeping track of changes that happen across a set of
获取一个用于跟踪一组文件中发生的更改的
files open a directory on your local system with an editor like vs code then
系统 使用 vs code 之类的编辑器打开本地系统上的目录，然后
run get an it from the command line you just created a git repository or repo it
运行从命令行获取它，您刚刚创建了一个 git 存储库或 repo 它
lives in this hidden get directory and keeps track of all the changes that
位于这个隐藏的位置 获取目录并跟踪
happen to these files as you work on a codebase you take snapshots or commits
在代码库上工作时这些文件发生的所有更改您拍摄快照或提交
of the current state of these files every commit has a unique ID and is
这些文件的当前状态每个提交都有一个唯一的 ID 并
linked to its parent and this means we can travel back in time to a previous
链接到其父级，这意味着我们可以旅行 及时回到
version of our files notice how our source control icon is lit up currently
我们文件的先前版本，注意我们的源代码控制图标是如何点亮的，目前
all of our files are untracked because we need to add them to the repo run get
我们所有的文件都没有被跟踪，因为我们需要将它们添加到 repo 运行 get
add to include or stage these files in the repo then create a snapshot of their
add 以在 repo 中包含或暂存这些文件，然后创建一个
current state by running git commit along with a message about what you did
通过运行 git commit 获取它们当前状态的快照以及关于你对这些文件做了什么的消息
to these files congratulations you just created the first commit on the
恭喜你刚刚
head of the master branch in this repo the changed files disappeared and you're
在这个 repo 的 master 分支的头部创建了第一个提交更改的文件 disap  peared 并且您
now on a clean working directory the head represents the most recent commit
现在在一个干净的工作目录中，
if we make some changes commit them to the repo the head moves forward but we
如果我们进行一些更改，则 head 代表最近
still have a reference to our previous commits so we can always go back to it
的提交
but the thing about software is that it's developed in a nonlinear fashion
但是关于软件的问题是它是以非线性方式开发的，
you might have multiple teams working on different features for the same codebase
你可能有多个团队同时为同一个代码库开发不同的功能，
simultaneously it makes that possible by branching create one by running git
它可以通过分支创建一个通过运行 git
branch and then rank it check out to move into that branch you can now safely
branch 然后对其进行排名检查以进入该分支 您现在可以安全
work on your feature in this branch without affecting the code or files in
地在此分支中处理您的功能，而不会影响主分支中的代码或文件
the master branch the commits you make here live in an alternate universe with
您在此处所做的提交存在于具有自己独特历史记录的备用宇宙中，
its own unique history at some point though you'll likely want to merge this
尽管您可能希望将此
history with the history and the master branch when you're ready go back to the
历史记录与 当你准备好时，历史记录和
master branch by running git checkout then run git merge on your
主分支通过运行 git checkout 返回主分支，然后在你的备用宇宙上运行 git merge 在
alternate-universe the tip of your feature branch now
你的 f 的尖端 eature 分支现在
becomes the head of the master branch where in other words our fragmented
成为 master 分支的负责人，换句话说，我们支离破碎的
universe has become one unless he ran into a merge conflict in which case
宇宙已经成为一个，除非他遇到合并冲突，在这种情况下，
you'll just have to wait for the sequel this has been get explained in 100
你只需要等待续集，如果你在 100 秒内得到解释
seconds if you want to see more short videos like this make sure to hit the
想看更多这样的短视频，记得
like button subscribe and let me know what you think in the comments thanks
按赞订阅，在评论里告诉我你的想法，
for watching and I will see you in the next one
谢谢收看，下期
you
再见